

- **9**491357016
- ★ Hyderbad,India
- Github 🗞
- **&** <u>LinkedIn</u>
- **Portfolio**

SKILLS

Programming skills:

 Python , C Language , PL/SQL , Shell Script

Databases:

 MySQL , SQL Server, Oracle Server, Mango dB

Frameworks:

• Flask , Django and tkinter.

Web Development:

• HTML, CSS and JavaScript

MLops:

• Circle CI, Mlflow, Docker and github actions

Cloud Platforms:

AWS, Heroku and Azure (Basics)

SUMMARY

1.7 years of IT work experience from TCS and 4 months of internship as a ML Engineer in ineuron.io, looking for transition to the **Data Scientist** Role. With interest in analyzing raw **data** and **statistics**, brings excellent communication abilities with hands-on experience in building **machine learning** models with **deployment**.

EXPERIENCE

Python Developer, TCS

Python backend developer

May2021-Present

- Writing efficient, reusable, testable, and scalable code.
- Understanding, analyzing, and implementing Business needs, feature modification requests, conversion into software components.
- Enhancing the functionalities of current software systems.
- Developing Backend components to enhance performance and receptiveness, server-side logic, and platform, statistical learning models, highly responsive web applications.
- Designing and implementing High availability and low latency applications, data protection and security features

Machine Learning Intern, ineuron.ai

Credit Card Default Prediction

June2021-Aug2022

- The main objective of this project is to predict the Credit Card defaulters based on their previous transaction's behaviors.
- Data set was taken from Kaggle and having more than 30000 records.
- Used different machine learning algorithms for training and finally random forest with hyperparameter tunning model gave highest accuracy with 83% and 80% of precision.
- I have also used k-means clustering algorithm to reduce the error.
- Deployed model as CI/CD pipeline by using Heroku with github actions.
- Code Link : Click here
- Internship Experience Letter

PROJECTS

IPL First Innings Score Prediction

June2021

- The main objective of this project is to predict score of ipl team based on that team previous 5 overs in the same match.
- This is a regression problem so I have used Linear regression model for training with accuracy of 80%.

Python Libraries:

- NumPy, Pandas
- Matplotlib, Seaborn. Plotly
- Scikit-learn
- TensorFlow
- Pickle
- Xgboost
- Beautiful Soup, Requests
- Flask, Django

Machine Learning Algorithms:

- Supervised ml algorithms
- Unsupervised ml algorithms

TOOLS

- PyCharm
- Anaconda
- Jupiter notebook
- vs code
- git and github
- google colab
- brackets, atom and sublime text

INTERESTS

- Coding and development
- Data science
- Artificial intelligence
- Playing with Data

- I have used Linear regression algo for model training and flask for api and used Heroku for deployment.
- For more details, please visit my Github code repo: Click Here

Diabetics Predication

May-2022

- The main objective of this project is to predict weather a woman having diabetics or not based on given some parameters.
- This is classification problem so I have trained my data with many machine learning algorithms finally Random Forest Classifier has given highest accuracy and recall value i.e. mor than 80%.
- For more details, please visit my Github code repo: Click Here

House Prices Prediction (Kaggle Competition)

April-2022

- The main objective of this project is to predict the sales price for each house. For each Id in the test set, you must predict the value of the Sale Price variable.
- It is a Advanced Problem of Regression which requires advanced techniques of feature engineering, feature selection and extraction, modeling, model evaluation, and Statistics.

Certifications

- Having Python certification <u>HackerRank</u>.
- Did Machine Learning certification from Udemy & ineuron
- SQL and HTML basics certification from geeksforgeeks.
- Python Django backend development certificate . <u>Click Here</u>

Education

Tudi ram reddy institute of technology & sciences(TRRIT) , Nalgonda

Computer Science Engineering

2016-2020

Sri Balaji Junior College , Hanamkonda

MPC 2014-2016

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 03-November-1997

Hobbies: Reading books & playing cricket.

Languages: English & Telugu & Hindi